# 前往柳州
Heading to Liuzhou)
# 在路上 想象着螺蛳粉的味道
Thinking about the flavor of luosifen on the way
(Luosifen: rice noodles in "luosi" river snail broth)
# 料真多
So many ingredients
# 这个好好吃的
This one tastes so good
# 一块钱一个
One yuan for each
# 要辣没
Spicy or not?
# 要
Spicy
# 要哦
# 哦哟
Whoa
# 好香哦
That smells so good
# 好好香的哦
It smells really good
# OK 了
It's now ready
# 热气腾腾一大碗
Such a big hot bowl
# 刚才盛菜的阿姨很可爱
That auntie serving luosifen was pretty cute
# 她的每一句话都是
Every sentence she said was like
# 阿姨告诉了你什么 什么 什么
"Let auntie tell you bla bla bla"
# 阿姨说了什么什么
"Auntie has said bla bla bla"
# 让人家感觉到 很亲切
Feels really friendly
# 你好 这个给谁
Excuse me, who should I give it to?
# 给我啊
To me
# 来 给阿姨
Come here, give it to auntie
# 好的
Alright
# 这边卖螺蛳粉的店
The luosifen restaurants here are like
# 它是差不多有两三个锅吧
They have about two pots or three
# 一个锅就是 不停地在翻热水
One pot has boiling water all the time
# 里面不停地在下米粉
where rice noodles are blanched all the time
# 还有一个锅 真的这个锅特别大
And there's another pot, a really large pot
# 里面是泡的豆腐泡 还有卤蛋
There are fried tofu and marinated eggs soaked inside
# 这个粉下好之后 要在里面
After blanching rice noodles
# 加上酸笋 辣椒 花生
we add sour bamboo shoot, chili and peanuts into it
# 然后是 哎呀
And then we have, ah-ya
# 一个个（加完后）再加卤蛋 豆腐泡
marinated egg and fried tofu following them
# 你看着的时候 都觉得好诱人
It's so appealing in front of you
# 尤其是当她捞出豆腐泡的那一刻
Especially when she scoops out the fried tofu
# 红油渗入到食材表面
and when the chili oil penetrates the ingredients
# 食欲大增
you are immediately appetized
# 你就会感觉到 不断地流口水
You can feel yourself drooling
# 好了 我们要开始了
Alright, let's get started
# 因为她最后是把大块的东西放在上面
She placed the largest ingredients on the top
# 但是它的下面是米粉 青菜
Below that, there are rice noodles and veggies
# 还有汤
and the broth
# 把它拌一下
Let's mix it
# 咱们要的是带汤的螺蛳粉
We ordered a luosifen noodle soup
# （1、带汤的螺蛳粉）
# （2、干拌的螺蛳粉）
# 它这边还有干拌的
(Option 1. Luosifen noodle soup)
(Option 2. Luosifen noodles without soup)
They also have a soup-less version
# （1、带汤的螺蛳粉）
# （2、干拌的螺蛳粉）
# 就是没有汤的
(Option 1. Luosifen noodle soup)
(Option 2. Luosifen noodles without soup)
which means there's no broth in it
# 咱们吃一个传统的就可以了
Let's just take a conventional one
# 我发现有个问题就是
I noticed one thing, that is
# 咱们端上来的时候 它这个腐竹还是干的
the tofu skin was still dry when we took the bowl here
# 但是 泡一泡 它就浸透了汤汁
But now, it's already soaked through in the broth
# 忍不住下口了
I can't resist it any more
# 先吃为敬
Bon appétit
# 哦 好辣呀
Oh, it's so spicy
# 它在下面有红油
There's chili oil under the ingredients
# 红油的辣味
The spiciness of the chili oil
# 真的是随着米粉一起 进入到口中
followed the rice noodles all the way into my mouth
# 因为我吃的第一口还有青菜
And there are veggies in my first bite
# 还能够吃到青菜 青脆 爽脆的口感
I could feel the freshness and crunchiness
# 米粉呢 就是很弹滑
The rice noodles are very al dente
# 这碗螺蛳粉 不仅是咸辣香
There are not only saltiness, spiciness and fragrance in this bowl of luosifen
# 还有一种酸酸的口感
But there's also a sourish mouthfeel
# 我告诉大家 如果说你不能吃辣
Let me tell you. In case you can't eat spicy food
# 到广西这边 一定要提前说
you must inform the restaurant when you are ordering food in Guangxi
# 因为他们的辣味 和我们的辣味
It's because, their "spicy" and our "spicy"
# 不是在一个水平线上
are at totally different levels
# 不能吃辣的人 一定要提前说
If you can't eat spicy food, you must let them know
# 我忘记说了 咱们要的这碗螺蛳粉
By the way, this bowl of luosifen we ordered
# 带汤的螺蛳粉是14块钱
This luosifen noodle soup costs 14 yuan
# 它（店）这里基础的是8块钱
The base price is 8 yuan here
# 但是 咱们又加了鸭脚还有卤蛋
However, we also added duck feet and marinated egg
# 所以说 一共是14块钱
So, together it's 14 yuan
# 我们就是在这么一个小破棚子里
That's how we are enjoying luosifen
# 吃我们的螺蛳粉
in this small ragged shed
# 吃完螺蛳粉后 有没有发现并没有见到螺蛳
Have you noticed that, we didn't see any "luosi" (river snail) even after finishing the luosifen
# 为了这个问题 我还特意问了这边的阿姨
Specifically for this question, I checked with the auntie
# 这个螺蛳粉 不是没有螺蛳吗
There is no "luosi" in this luosifen, is there?
# （吃的时候没发现）
# 为什么叫螺蛳粉
(Didn't notice it when eating)
Then why is it called "luosifen"?
# 他那个螺蛳用来煮汤
The luosi are stewed in the broth
# 就是在汤里面
They are in the broth
# 其实在大家的印象当中
People have the impression that
# 螺蛳粉是 不酸 不臭 不正宗
authentic luosifen must be sour and smelly
# 但是到这边吃螺蛳粉 你会发现
However, if you have luosifen here, you'll probably notice
# 并没有这么夸张
that impression seems to be overstated
# 这边的阿姨解释到
The auntie here explained that
# 这个酸臭味主要来自于酸笋
the sourness and smells come from the sour bamboo shoot
# 但是她们认为 这个
However, in their idea
# 酸笋没有什么特别的味道
sour bamboo shoot doesn't have any weird smell
# 只不过说外地人可能闻不惯
Except that non-locals might not be used to it
# 觉得 很酸很臭 接受不了
They may think it's too sour and too smelly to accept
# 臭味来自酸笋
The smell comes from sour bamboo shoot
# 那你没有吃 你吃了没有
So have you tried that? Did you eat any of it?
# 吃了酸笋 没觉得臭啊
I had the sour bamboo shoot. Not smelly at all
# 不臭啊 很好吃啊 对不对
Not smelly but very tasty, right?
# 对
Right
# 我们酸笋不臭的 一点不臭
Our sour bamboo shoot is not smelly. Not smelly at all
# 解开了一个未解之谜
That's how a myth is busted
# 不过 也有味道大的螺蛳粉
However, there are also more smelly variants
# 来这家店 比较有意思的一个地方就是
There's something interesting about this restaurant
# 还未靠近这家店
Even if you are still at a distance from it
# 就能够闻到螺蛳粉的味道
you can already smell the luosifen
# 就是那种酸臭酸臭的味道
which are the sour and smelly kind of smells
# 关 注 雪 鱼 探 店
(Subscribe)